JORDAN EVANS

07306266826 \$\dipprox \text{jordanleeevans@hotmail.com}\$

https://jordanevans.vercel.app \display www.github.com/jordanleeevans

ABOUT ME

I am a highly driven software engineer, with nearly four years of industry experience. My background has a strong focus on data, ranging from database architecture to building machine learning models from scratch. Outside of work you can find me skateboarding, practicing my barista skills with my beloved espresso machine or cracking on with a new programming project. Oh, and video games ofcourse.

EDUCATION

University of Bristol

Sep 2016 - June 2020

Master of Physics, First Class Honours.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Yard June 2023 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

- · Manage a high-volume data collection and processing service, handling over 1 million daily requests. This includes proactive monitoring and troubleshooting to ensure smooth operations and immediate response to any anomalies.
- · Oversee the AWS infrastructure: Keeping the Security Groups up to date, deploying and updating EC2 instances using the AWS console, boto3 Python SDK and leveraging AMI images. Reviewing AWS cost reports and taking appropriate action to minimise unnecessary costs.
- · Frequently participating in organisational learning sessions, explaining complex topics to non-technical audiences. Some talks include *Infrastructure as Code*, *Multi-touch Page Attribution*, *Keyword Content Analysis via tf-idf*.
- · Independently develop and maintain deep learning models for complex problems like: multi-touch page attribution, impression modelling and automated keyword generation.
- · Added Promtail as a system service, scraping our cron logs and pushing them to an internal Loki client. Created a Grafana dashboard to surface the scraped logs for improved system monitoring.
- · Increased the robustness of our machine learning repository by adding a Pytest suite to the CI/CD pipeline.
- · Mentoring 2-3 developers with backend and database best practices, provisioning their host and virtual machines for development, and advocating for their needs with HR to secure better equipment.
- · Actively participate in retrospectives, providing constructive feedback on past sprint performance, suggesting areas for improvement in upcoming sprints, and fostering open dialogue by actively listening to peer opinions.

Yard Aug 2021 - June 2023

Data/Backend Engineer

- · Developed server-side logic and APIs, focusing on Python (Django) and MySQL, adhering to SOLID principles.
- · Employed test driven development using libraries such as Pytest, Unittest, and Playwright. Utilised common test paradigms including unit, functional, end-to-end and integration tests.
- · Created data pipelines, stored procedures, and normalised databases.

· Spearheaded a successful partnership with DAPTEC at Cardiff Met University where I developed an optical character recognition (OCR) python tool, leveraging Googles OCR AI, to parse hundreds of diary entries. This was part of a collaboration with Techniquest, a science discovery centre in Cardiff, where the exhibit still exists today.

X4 Software Nov 2020 - July 2021

Digital Analytics Manager/Software Development

- · Worked with jQuery and Mocha to ensure the web scraping logic was up to date.
- · Applied problem-solving and statistical modelling skills, and learned JavaScript.
- · Developed key professional traits including effective communication, time management, and software development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient Languages Python, MySQL
Competent Languages JavaScript

Databases MySQL

Web Development Django, React, HTML, CSS

DevOps AWS, Docker, Ansible, Linux, Containerisation, Virtualisation

Version Control Git, Bitbucket

Tools VSCode, Vim, Grafana, RegEx, InfluxDB, HeidiSQL Machine Learning TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Keras, Pandas

WORK PROJECTS

Multi-touch Page Attribution

Implemented a deep neural net with attention for multi-touch page attribution. This project saw end-to-end data pipeline creation, AWS infrastructure leveraging: S3 buckets, Security Groups, AMI images, EC2 instances, and database normalisation. This project delivered critical insights to our clients, allowing them to effectively analyse individual pages and how they contribute to driving customer conversion.

Keyword Content Analysis

Search engine optimisation is fundamental to enhancing a business's online presence, this project focused on optimising our clients keyword pool such that all keywords were relevant to their goals. To address this need, I developed a keyword content analysis tool. This tool employs a web data API to scrape the entirety of a client's website, fortnightly. The content is processed and stored in our database. The data is then parsed to a custom tf-idf algorithm, where each active SEO keyword is compared against the website content, and subsequently scored. Keyword content analysis has significantly reduced the manual work, freeing up the in-house SEO team to work on more strategic tasks such as content planning and strategy development.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Self-hosting services with Docker

In my own time I have an on-going project where I have repurposed an old PC as a server. I host a variety of services through Docker, some of these include: Jellyfin for media streaming, TrueNAS for storage, Traefik as a reverse proxy, PiHole for network-wide ad blocking and DNS. All of these services are maintained using Infrastructure as Code, via Ansible playbooks. Running these services locally has provided me with valuable skills regarding cyber security, network configurations, and VPNs for secure connections. In the future I plan to upgrade this setup to a Kubernetes cluster to introduce redundancy and ensure a fail-over DNS, particularly my PiHole service.